<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">
    <string name="app_name">KitharaM</string>
    <string name="kithara">Kithara</string>
    <string name="dhach">Don\'t have Account?</string>
    <string name="welcome">Welcome</string>
    <string name="forgot_password">Forgot password</string>
    <string name="remember_me">Remember me</string>
    <string name="sign_up">Sign-up</string>
    <string name="log_instudent">As Student</string>
    <string name="log_intutor">As Tutor</string>
    <string name="register">Register</string>
    <string name="password">Password</string>
    <string name="re_password">Confirm Password</string>
    <string name="email">Email</string>
    <string name="username">Username</string>
    <string name="example_gmail_com">example@gmail.com</string>
    <string name="psastiris">*******</string>
    <string name="login">Login</string>
    <string name="Conpass">Confirm password</string>
    <string name="email_address">Email Address</string>
    <string name="yrinfos">Please login with your account as Student</string>
    <string name="yrinfot">Please login with your account as tutor</string>
    <string name="title_activity_navi">navi</string>
    <string name="first_fragment_label">First Fragment</string>
    <string name="second_fragment_label">Second Fragment</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="previous">Previous</string>
    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="loginpssword">Password</string>
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="already_have_account">Already have account?</string>
    <string name="fpwrd">Forgot Password</string>
    <string name="getmail">Enter you email</string>

    <string name="beginner1">
         <b>Acoustic guitars</b> are traditional, hollow-bodied instruments with a sound hole in the center,
        allowing strings to resonate and project sound outward. They come in various shapes and sizes,
        influencing their tonal characteristics. Players play by plucking or strumming the strings with
        fingers or a pick, suitable for various genres like folk, country, classical, and contemporary music.

    </string>

    <string name="beginner2">
        Meanwhile, the <b>electric guitar</b> is a modern, versatile instrument with a solid or semi-solid
        body and electronic components. It uses magnetic pickups to convert string vibrations into electrical signals,
        which are then sent to an amplifier for manipulation. Its versatility makes it popular in genres like rock,
        blues, jazz, and metal.
    </string>

    <string name="beginner3">
        <u>Strings</u> are crucial parts of music because they convert vibrations
        into harmonic notes that express mood and creative purpose. They are essential
        to the sound produced by many instruments, such as violins and guitars.


        The material, gauge, and tension of strings contribute to
        the distinctive timbre and character of an instrument, allowing musicians to craft a
        diverse palette of tones. From the intimate intimacy of a single plucked string to the harmonious synergy of a full orchestra,
        strings remain an essential element in the enchanting symphony of music.
    </string>

    <string name="beginner4">
        Basic chords are the fundamental terms in music, the building blocks upon which limitless melodies and
        harmonies are constructed. By utilizing basic note combinations that are created by arranging three or more
        tones simply, one can unlock the expressive potential of musical instruments. These arrangements establish
        the harmonic structure that underlies and builds musical works, whether they be performed on the
        piano, guitar, or any other chord-capable instrument.

        From the timeless simplicity of major and minor chords to the richer textures of seventh chords,
        understanding and mastering these basic chord structures opens a world of creative possibilities for
        musicians. Assembling these musical puzzle pieces not only provides a solid framework for composition but also
        empowers musicians to communicate emotions, tell stories, and evoke powerful sentiments through the universal language of chords.
    </string>

    <string name="beginner5" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
       " Ever heard a song that makes your foot tap and head bob? That's the magic of rhythm,
        the heartbeat of music that drives melodies and sends shivers down your spine. And guess what?
        You can become the master of that pulse, the ruler of the groove, with a little practice and the
        right tools!"

    </string>

    <string name="beginner6" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        "Forget shredding solos for now; rhythm guitar is about playing down the foundation,
        the steady beat that keeps the music pumping. Think of strumming chords, keeping time
        with the drums, and adding tasteful accents to complement the melody. It's like the glue
        that holds a song together, and it's surprisingly versatile."


    </string>
    <string name="beginner7" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
       " Why learn basic Rhythm? Mastering rhythm unlocks a whole new world of musical possibilities.
        Here's why you should jump on this groovy bandwagon:"
          </string>
    <string name="beginner7a" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
      Play with others: Join bands, jam sessions, and acoustic circles! Rhythm guitar is the social butterfly
           of music, making you indispensable in any musical setting.
  </string>
    <string name="beginner7b" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        Unlock songwriting: Building songs starts with a good rhythm section.
    Learning rhythm guitar gives you the building blocks to craft your own musical creations.
  </string>
    <string name="beginner7c" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        Support the melody: Think of rhythm guitar as the loyal sidekick to the lead singer.
    Your role is to add texture, accentuate phrasing, and set the mood for the song.
  </string>
    <string name="beginner7d" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
       Improve your overall playing: Rhythmic skills translate to all aspects of guitar playing, from soloing to finger picking.

    </string>

    <string name = "beginner9">
        To read this, you can set your metronome to 60 bpm (beats per minute). In the case of whole notes,
        you need to count 4 beats as you extend either the sound (i.e. a note or chord on your instrument) or
        the silence between notes. The same applies to the half notes, where you need to extend sound for 2 beats.
        And finally, the quarter notes where the sound or silence equals to 1 beat.


        Interpreting eight notes requires understanding beat division, which is divided into downbeat
        and upbeat in simple meter. Pay attention to hand movements during tapping, as they create sound and
        prepare for next tap.
    </string>

    <string name="beginner10">
        This means that you will have to play two sounds
        that equally divide 1 beat. One that hits the downbeat and the other that hits the upbeat:
    </string>

    <string name="beginner11" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        "Harmony is achieved when multiple notes or voices play simultaneously, creating a pleasing sound.
        Chord progressions and chords, which consist of three or more notes, support or complement the melody.
        Combining vocal parts, such as the combined voices of a choir, also contributes to harmony,
        creating a harmonious sound.

        Harmony can be divided into dissonant and consonant types. Dissonant harmony adds unpleasant notes,
        creating tension and instability in chords. This tension is released by resolving to consonant chords,
        such as seconds, sevenths, and ninths. Consonant harmony, on the other hand, is stable and pleasing,
        with intervals that smoothly transition between constant chords.
        Combining these harmonies enhances music's excitement and intrigue."

    </string>

    <string name="beginner12">
       Melody is a musical phrase consisting of multiple notes or voices, often the most memorable part of a song,
        often created with instruments or vocals, and often repeats in compositions.

      Melody consists of two main elements: Pitch and Rhythm. Pitch determines note sound, while Rhythm determines duration.
        Melodies have two types of melodic motion: Conjunct and Disjunct, with Conjunct being comfortable and Disjunct being difficult and less memorable.
    </string>

    <string name="beginner13" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        "Music theory is the grammar and vocabulary of music, guiding the combination of elements like notes, scales, chords, and rhythm to create
        meaningful music, providing rules and guidelines."

    </string>
    <string name="beginnersub_13" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        "Why Learn Music Theory? Music theory provides a roadmap for a musician's musical journey,
        enhancing their understanding of music, and enabling better analysis, improvisation, and composition.
        It also enhances their playing skills by mastering techniques, and understanding chord progressions, and timing.
        It also facilitates seamless collaboration with other musicians, allowing for creativity and breaking rules."
    </string>

    <string name="beginner14" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        "Here's a roadmap to kick off your music theory exploration:

        The Musical Alphabet: The musical alphabet, consisting of notes on the staff, is a fundamental building block in music,
        serving as the code for understanding and speaking the language of music."

    </string>
    <string name="beginnersub_14" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">

        The musical alphabet, consisting of seven letters A, B, C, D, E, F, and G, includes the first seven notes within an octave,
        encompassing eight distinct pitches. These notes can be "high" or "low" within the octave, allowing for a diverse musical range.
        Think of the staff as a musical ladder with five lines and four spaces. Each line and space has a designated letter name,
        starting with E on the bottom line and ascending A-C-E-G on the lines and F-D-B on the spaces. This pattern repeats above and
        below the staff, venturing into higher and lower octaves.

    </string>

    <string name="beginner15">
      " -  Learn The notes On The Guitar -
        Mastering the guitar fretboard is crucial for finding chords. With practice and tricks,
        it's easier than initially thought, making it a valuable skill to acquire."

    </string>

    <string name="beginner16">
        Sharps and flats are half-steps away from natural notes, with sharps being a half-step up and flats being the opposite.
        Movement changes the note, with sharps being a half-step above a natural note and flats being the opposite.
        The name of a single note depends on the key.
        (Pro Tip: An easy way to keep your sharps and flats straight is to think of stepping on a bug.
        When you step down on the bug, it’s flat, just like notes on your guitar).
    </string>

    <string name="beginner17" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        The BC and EF Rule
All natural notes have sharps and flats between them except BC and EF. A half-step between these leads to the next natural note. Stepping up from B leads you to C. Stepping down from F leads to E.

    </string>
    <string name="beginnersub_17" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">

Count Up The Frets On Each String
To maintain order on the fretboard, count up notes by half-stepping up from the string name or note, following BC and EF rules.

    </string>

    <string name="beginner18">
        12th Fret Octave
        Now for the next trick in helping you learn the guitar fretboard. You only need to learn the first 12 frets
        as the notes begin repeating. For instance, look at the B String image above. On fret 12, the note
        becomes B again. Fret 13 would then be C, the same as fret 1. That’s much less to learn.
    </string>
    <string name="beginnersub_18">


        Putting It All Together
        Mastering the musical alphabet is essential for understanding music,
        collaborating with other musicians, unlocking improvisation, and composing music.
        It allows you to decipher sheet music, communicate with other musicians,
        and create melodies and harmonies. By understanding the notes, you can unleash your inner
        musician and create your own musical story.
    </string>

    <string name="beginner19">
        Have you ever heard a song that makes your foot tap or your head bob uncontrollably? That steady pulse driving the music is
        likely the metronome, your trusty rhythm partner in any musical journey.
        This introduction explores the role of the metronome in music, highlighting its potential
        to enhance playing and unlock the joy of precise rhythm, despite its perceived intimidating nature for some.
    </string>
    <string name="beginner20">

        What is a Metronome?
        A metronome, whether it be a mechanical or digital app, is a device that produces a constant beat at a preset tempo, aiding in the maintenance of a regular rhythm during practice or performance.
    </string>
    <string name="beginner21" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">

Why Use a Metronome?
By delivering an internal ear for a precise beat, a metronome helps enhance timing. It improves accuracy and prevents tempo fluctuations by training the internal clock. This
method ensures tight arrangements and rhythmic coherence by boosting confidence, opening up grooves, and preparing artists to interact with others.
    </string>
    <string name="beginner22" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"The metronome shouldn't scare you! To help you get started, consider these easy steps:
        Start slow with a comfortable pace and focus on precise and neat playing with the metronome. Gradually increase the
        tempo as you feel comfortable, remembering consistency over speed. Use the metronome to practice new
        rhythms and patterns, like syncopation, eighth notes, and triplets. Enjoy the process by playing along
        with music or creating your own rhythms."

    </string>

    <!-- Intermediate-->


    <string name="intermediate" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">

       "Stepping into the intermediate guitarist's realm marks a significant juncture on the musical journey,
        where proficiency meets exploration and creativity blossoms. At this stage, players transcend the
        basics, delving into more intricate techniques, nuanced expressions, and a broader repertoire of chords
        and scales. With a solid foundation in hand, intermediate guitarists embark on a dynamic exploration of their
        instrument, honing their skills in finger style, advanced strumming patterns, and melodic improvisation.


        The quest for mastery becomes intertwined with the pursuit of personal style, as players experiment with
        diverse genres and develop a more discerning ear for tone and phrasing. It's a stage where the joy of
        playing transforms into a deeper artistic connection, paving the way for a richer and more nuanced musical expression."
    </string>
    <string name="intermediate_sub" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        "Barre chords stand as a pivotal milestone in a guitarist's journey, representing a leap into more
        sophisticated fretboard mastery and harmonic versatility. Unlike open chords, barre chords involve
        using a single finger to press down across multiple strings, allowing for the transposition of familiar
        chord shapes up and down the neck. This technique not only expands the guitarist's reach but also opens
        the door to a myriad of musical possibilities."
      </string>

    <string name="intermediate2" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
       " Barre chords are a technique that enhances a guitarist's fretboard skills and opens up a
        wide range of musical possibilities. They use a single finger to form a "bar" across multiple strings, acting as a movable capo.
        This flexibility allows players to shift chord shapes seamlessly up and down the neck. As intermediate guitarists
        tackle complex compositions, barre chords enable fluid transitions between major and minor chords and richer voicing.
        This technique fosters creativity and contributes to a distinctive playing style.

        Barre chords are a technique that enhances a guitarist's fretboard skills and opens up a
        wide range of musical possibilities. They use a single finger to form a "bar" across multiple strings,
        acting as a movable capo. This flexibility allows for seamless chord shape shifts, deepening harmonic
        relationships and improvisational skills. Mastering barre chords not only refines technical proficiency but
        also broadens the musician's musical palette for more expressive performances."

        </string>

    <string name="intermediate3" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
       "Power Chord/5th Chords - Your Instant Guide to Unlocking Awesome Riffs!
        Ready to unleash your inner rockstar and crank out those heavy guitar riffs?
        Then buckle up, because today's lesson dives into the world of power chords,
        your key to creating powerful, distorted sounds in a flash!"

    </string>
    <string name="intermediate3a" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        "Why it's Exceptional? Imagine chords that are simple to play, sound massive, and fuel countless rock
        and metal anthems. That's the magic of power chords! Unlike regular chords with multiple notes,
        these bad boys use just two notes: the root and the fifth of a major scale. Think of them as the
        "muscle cars" of chords - lean, mean, and built for speed."
    </string>
    <string name="intermediate3b" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        "Why the Number 5? The number 5 you see written next to a power chord's name (e.g., E5)
        tells us it contains the root and the fifth interval of a major scale. So, an E5 chord would have
        the notes E (root) and B (fifth), creating that signature powerful sound."
    </string>
    <string name="intermediate3c" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        Finding Your Power:
        Power chords are flexible guitar workhorses that serve as the foundation for many different rock,
        metal, punk, and blues genres. They can be utilized for riffs, progressions,
        and to boost power. Riffs provide rhythmic support, progressions provide tension and
        release, and adding power boosts sonic power. Combining power chords with ordinary chords increases
        adaptability. Practice forming the basic power chord shape with fingers and clean string muting.
        Start with simple 2-chord progressions like E5-A5 or D5-G5, using a metronome for strumming patterns.

    </string>

    <string name="intermediate3d" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        "Explore different positions: Move your power chord shape up and down the fretboard to discover new sounds.
        Practice and master power chords by jamming along to your favorite songs, and identifying the
        chords used in rock and metal. With dedication, you'll create your headbanging riffs and unleash your inner rockstar."
    </string>
    <string name="intermediate3e" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
Introduction to Polyrhythms:
Polyrhythm involves layering different strumming patterns and note durations, pushing rhythmic boundaries and utilizing multiple rhythms that are not easily identifiable as simple manifestations of the same meter.

Polyrhythms are an advanced style of rhythm. If you do not have a basic understanding of rhythm already, this instructional series may be a bit over your head, and too difficult to understand. Even if you DO have a basic understanding of rhythm, polyrhythms are challenging to play and understand.
    </string>
    <string name="intermediate3f" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"What IS a polyrhythm?
The word POLY means MANY. So, in simple terms, a polyrhythm means many rhythms. Steve Vai, in his paper called "Tempo Mental", says, "A polyrhythm is just what it says. Two rhythms, or “feels”, happening at the same time." However, it IS a bit more complicated than that.

Why? Because if it were simply the case of having different "rhythms" being played at once, I would argue that most music uses polyrhythms. The drums, guitars, vocals, etc. are not all playing the same rhythm pattern all the time. However, this does not make a polyrhythm. A polyrhythm is used to create tension in a song. By placing at least two different rhythms together that sound somewhat "off" you can create something that stands out to the listener's ear.

Why? Because if it were simply the case of having different "rhythms" being played at once, I would argue that most music uses polyrhythms. The drums, guitars, vocals, etc. are not all playing the same rhythm pattern all the time. However, this does not make a polyrhythm. A polyrhythm is used to create tension in a song. By placing at least two different rhythms together that sound somewhat "off" you can create something that really stands out to the listener's ear.

When you see something like a triplet, quintuplet, sextuplet, nonuplet, etc., you're probably dealing with a polyrhythm. Notes grouped in this fashion will have some indication that they are not naturally found within the given time signature you are playing in.

The circled numbers are indicating a deviation from what's normally found in this time signature. The numbers
        are telling you how to space these notes that would not occur, naturally, in the given time signature.
        You could also notate the same thing like this:"
    </string>

    <string name="intermediate4" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"Inversion -
Guitar chord inversions enable the creation of various voicings for a specific chord, thereby enhancing the flavor, variety, and ease of playing, while also providing additional versatility. In this lesson, we’ll take a look at what chord inversions are and how to identify them on the guitar fretboard.

What are guitar chord inversions?
While the concept of a chord inversion may sound complicated, it’s quite simple.

Guitar chord inversions involve changing the arrangement of stacked notes, causing the root note to move from the bass position. It's important to avoid the same root position power chord and explore higher inversions on the fretboard for wider ranges and smoother transitions.
    </string>


    <string name="intermediate5"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"Tempo Manipulation:

Before you go a changing’…

Guitar play depends heavily on dynamics, which are the changes in loudness between notes or phrases. They make melodies stand out, generate strong feelings, and turn a composition from boring to amazing. Tension and release are improved by creating dramatic swells, sharp bursts, and ghost notes.

Since chaotic rhythm is frequently justified as artistic or expressive, rhythm stability is essential for expressive performances. Students who mimic recordings and use expressive rhythmic tools rather than reading the rhythms on the score are likely to have poor rhythm. The impact of any expressive use of rhythm is diminished if it is not possible to play in time. Thus, mastering the art of playing in time is a prerequisite for mastering timing.

Timing is everything. To achieve steady rhythm, it's crucial to know where to implement expressive rhythmic changes. Scores often indicate places to change tempo, and reading them with seriousness is essential. Common tempo rhythm changes include accelerando and decelerandos, which create urgency or dramatic build-up. While some may be found in a musical dictionary, many are rarely used. It's important to explore different speeds within riffs to create a sense of urgency.

Jam with Pros(Virtually)
Utilize online backing tracks featuring complex drum and bass parts to push your improvisation skills and apply your newfound techniques in a musical context."
</string>
    <string name="intermediate6"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"Remember, Mastery in music requires dedication, passion, experimentation, pushing boundaries, and making mistakes. Embrace the journey and soon, you'll be unleashing powerful chord riffs."
</string>

    <string name="intermediate6a"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        <b>Guitar solo</b>
    </string>

    <string name="intermediate7"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
    "Ever heard a guitar solo that sends shivers down your spine? That jaw-dropping moment when the music explodes into a whirlwind of melody and emotion? That's the magic of solo guitar, and here's your chance to learn its secrets!

Soloing involves expressing oneself through music, creating unique melodies, and adding flavor to one's playing, allowing one to tell a story without the need for words.

Imagine stepping into a musical spotlight, all eyes on you
        and your trusty six-string companion. You start with
        a simple chord progression, then boom! Your fingers take
        flight, dancing across the strings, weaving notes into vibrant tapestries of sound.
        You bend strings, unleash harmonics, and let your passion flow through the frets. That's
        the essence of solo guitar - improvisation, creativity, and pure musical expression.

A guitar solo isn't just a flashy display of technical tricks;
        it's a musical conversation, a chance to let your guitar sing
        without words. It's the moment you step into the musical spotlight
        and tell your story through vibrant melodies, soaring bends, and rhythmic grooves."
    </string>
    <string name="intermediate7a"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"So, what exactly is a guitar solo all about?
        1. Improvisation - it’s about creating distinctive melodies using scales, chords, and
        techniques, akin to painting with sound, allowing the expression of emotions and musical ideas."
 </string>
    <string name="intermediate7b"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        "2.Creativity- It's about crafting unique melodic lines on the fly,
        using scales, chords, and techniques as your musical palette.
        Think of it as painting with sound, expressing your emotions and musical
        ideas through improvised phrases."
 </string>
    <string name="intermediate7c"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"3.Expression - It's about crafting unique
        melodic lines on the fly, using scales, chords, and
        techniques as your musical palette. Think of it as painting
        with sound, expressing your emotions and musical ideas through improvised phrases."
 </string>
    <string name="intermediate7d"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"4. Rhythm and Timing - It's about crafting unique melodic lines on the fly, using scales, chords, and techniques as your musical palette.
        Think of it as painting with sound, expressing your emotions and musical ideas through improvised phrases."
 </string>
    <string name="intermediate7e"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"5. Techniques and Tricks -  It's about crafting unique melodic lines on the fly, using scales, chords, and techniques as your musical palette. Think of it as painting with sound, expressing your emotions and musical ideas through improvised phrases."
    </string>
    <string name="intermediate8"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"But where do you start? Don't worry, rockstar-in-training! We'll break down soloing into bite-sized steps, guiding you from basic building blocks to mind-blowing melodies. Here's a sneak peek into your soloing journey:"

         </string>
    <string name="intermediate8a"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
Chords: Master chords first! Why? Its crucial for building musical strength, unlocking music theory, jamming with songs, and boosting soloing confidence, providing a solid foundation for your guitar journey.
 </string>
    <string name="intermediate8b"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"Scales: Scales are the musical playgrounds where soloists like to hang out. We'll learn the pentatonic scale, your first soloing BFF, and explore its different shapes and sounds."
 </string>
    <string name="intermediate8c"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"Rhythm and Timing: Soloing isn't just about random notes. We'll learn how to groove with the rhythm section, keep tight timing, and build tension and release within your solos."
 </string>
    <string name="intermediate8d"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"Phrasing and articulations: Think of it as the punctuation of your musical sentences. We'll learn how to use phrasing and articulation to add emotion and character to your solos, making them sing and shout."
 </string>
    <string name="intermediate8e"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"Techniques: The bag of tricks! We'll explore bending strings, tapping, adding vibrato, and other cool techniques to give your solos some extra flavor."
 </string>
    <string name="intermediate8f"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"Practice and Patience: Soloing takes time and dedication. Don't get discouraged, keep practicing, and watch your confidence and skills soar."


Remember, the journey to soloing mastery is full of fun, challenges, and endless possibilities. So, grab your guitar, crank up the amp, and get ready to unleash your inner rockstar!

    </string>
    <string name="intermediate9"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
<b>Guitar tablature </b>is a musical map, with six horizontal lines representing strings, with the thickest (E) at the top and the thinnest (e) at the bottom. Frets on the neck and the nut at the bottom represent the 0th fret.
  </string>
    <string name="intermediate9a"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
To determine the fret position on each string, use the numbers on the lines, such as pressing the finger on the third fret of the A string.
      </string>
    <string name="intermediate9b"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
P.M.: Palm Mute - Lightly rest the palm of your picking hand on the strings near the bridge for a muted sound.
  </string>
    <string name="intermediate9c"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
b: Bend - Raise the pitch of a note by pushing the string up with your fretting finger.
</string>
    <string name="intermediate9d"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
h: Hammer-on - Play a note by quickly bringing your finger down onto a fret without picking the string.
</string>
    <string name="intermediate9e"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
p: Pull-off - Lift your finger off a fret to sound a note, the opposite of a hammer-on.
</string>
    <string name="intermediate9f"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
/: SLide - Slide your finger up or down the fretboard to play a succession of notes.
</string>
    <string name="intermediate9g"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
V or D: Pick Upward or Pick Downward - Indicates the direction of your pick stroke.

    </string>
    <string name="intermediate10" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
Techniques
Alternate Picking: a precision technique that involves switching between downstrokes and upstrokes on each note, resulting in a clean and consistent sound.
 </string>
    <string name="intermediate10a" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
Palm Muting: Yearning to infuse your riffs with bite and aggression? Enter palm muting, your secret weapon! Palm muting is a technique that adds texture and grit to your musical arsenal by gently resting your palm on the strings near the bridge.
 </string>
    <string name="intermediate10b" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
Sweep Picking: Brace yourself to shred! Sweep picking involves picking consecutive notes across multiple strings, creating fast, arpeggiated passages, and creating a controlled destruction trail.
 </string>
    <string name="intermediate10c" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
String Bending: Become the maestro of string manipulation! String bending is the art of pushing a string up or down to alter its pitch, creating those iconic bluesy bends and soaring high notes. Envision your finger engaging in a wrestling match with the string, bending it to your musical will!
 </string>
    <string name="intermediate10d" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
Vibrato: Ever craved those soulful bends and wails in guitar solos? Enter vibrato! Vibrato, a technique in guitar solos, involves gently shaking the string to infuse emotion into notes, introducing depth and expressiveness to the musical canvas.
 </string>
    <string name="intermediate10e" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        Bonus Tip: Above all, revel in the joy of playing! Experiment freely, combine these techniques, and carve out your unique sonic signature. The six-string journey is a boundless exploration, so let your creativity flow and embrace the infinite possibilities!
</string>
    <string name="intermediate11"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
Ever craved to add richness and depth to your guitar playing? Then embark on the enchanting journey of arpeggios, musical nuggets that hold the keys to unlocking beautiful melodies and sparkling harmonies. Forget chugging power chords for now; arpeggios offer a delicate, note-by-note approach that unlocks new melodic and harmonic possibilities on your fretboard.

        </string>
    <string name="intermediate12"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">

"So, what are arpeggios?

Imagine taking a chord, like a juicy apple, and slicing it thin, savoring each note one by one. That's what an arpeggio is: a chord's notes played in succession, rather than strummed all at once. It's like a melody hidden within the chord, waiting to be unraveled and explored."
 </string>
    <string name="intermediate12a"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">

Arpeggios offer a variety of melodic options, enhancing soloing and phrasing. They provide a deeper understanding of chords and their internal relationships, enhancing finger dexterity. To learn arpeggios, master major and minor scales, start with simple chords, explore patterns, add rhythm and groove, bridge gaps between chords, and master arpeggio shapes and positions.
 </string>
    <string name="intermediate12b"  tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
Arpeggios can be used to craft compelling melodies, explore chord progressions, and serve as a springboard for improvisation. By exploring different arpeggio shapes and positions, players can play arpeggios in different locations and connect them across keys. Ultimately, arpeggios are a powerful tool for improvising with pentatonic patterns.
    </string>

    <!--    Advance    -->

    <string name="advance">
Advanced guitarists learn transformative approaches that combine technical prowess with creativity.
        They defy conventions by utilizing rich harmonies and virtuoso performances. Their masterful
        chord voicings and sophisticated fingerstyle compositions push the boundaries of their trade.

CAGED is a technique that helps guitarists unlock the
        full potential of the fretboard by associating five major chord shapes (C, A G, E, and D) with
        their corresponding scale patterns, enabling smooth interconnection and repeatable major scale sequences.
    </string>

    <string name="advance1" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">

This allows for effortless navigation between various scale positions, enabling the creation of smooth melodies and solos. CAGED is a transformative tool for guitarists, allowing them to use the entire fretboard for creative improvisation. It offers flexibility, allowing seamless transition between chord voicings and scale positions, enabling creative possibilities for composition, improvisation, and playing in various musical contexts.

         </string>

    <string name="advance1a" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
The <b>major scale</b> is a crucial guitar technique for mastering chords, creating melodies, and delivering expressive solos. Its structure, consisting of seven notes, produces a "happy" or "bright" sound, as seen in tunes like "Twinkle, Twinkle Little Star."

The formula, consisting of whole and half steps, is the foundation for creating major scales on the guitar. Memorizing this formula helps guitarists navigate the fretboard confidently. Learning various scale shapes, covering different parts of the neck, offers diverse phrasing possibilities.
         </string>

    <string name="advance1b" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
Music sheets and tabs are essential tools for musicians to translate
        written symbols into musical expression. They convey melody, rhythm, and harmony through notations,
        while tabs simplify the process with numbers and strings, particularly for guitarists. Mastering
        these guides allows musicians to breathe life into compositions, bridging the gap between notation and
        emotive performance. To effectively utilize this resource, practice with the C major scale at a slow pace,
        gradually increasing tempo as proficiency is achieved. Emphasize accurate finger placement,
        align with designated numbers, and strive for a clean tone. Mastery of the C major scale enhances technical proficiency and equips musicians to tackle other major scales.
    </string>

    <string name="advance2" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">

        The <b>natural minor scale</b>, also known as the Aeolian mode, stands as a hidden gem in the arsenal of guitarists, casting a spell with its seven notes that conjure a dark and dreamy sonic landscape—an ideal addition to infuse a distinctive essence into your playing.
    </string>
    <string name="advance3" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
How to Acquire the Natural Minor Scale?
 </string>

    <string name="advance3a" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"Start with a Major Scale: Begin with a major scale; for instance, let's take C major (C D E F G A B C).
Adjust Some Notes: Lower the 3rd, 6th, and 7th notes. In the case of C major, E becomes Eb, G transforms into Ab,
        and B changes to Bb.
Voila! You've crafted the C natural minor scale (C D Eb F G Ab Bb)."
 </string>

    <string name="advance3b" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
Why is it exceptional? The natural minor scale has a unique sound due to its arrangement of whole and half steps. It allows for versatile finger positions and can be used to construct minor, minor seventh, and dominant seventh chords. The minor scale can be used to create enchanting riffs, solos, and chord progressions, making it a versatile tool for various musical styles.
 </string>
    <string name="advance3c" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"The natural minor scale is an artistic journey that offers a vast range of emotions and
        expressions, including haunting melodies, captivating chord progressions, and improvisation.
        It's a key to a rich and diverse musical landscape, so pick up your guitar and let your creativity flow.

Delving into the realm of the A natural minor scale, our first line takes you on a journey
        across the strings, starting at the 5th fret of the A string and ascending to the
        12th fret on the G string. Line two introduces arpeggios, a methodical approach to
        conquering the scale note by note, up and down the strings. Follow the designated picking
        pattern above each note - down, down, up, up, down, down, up. Master this, and you'll be
        arpeggio-ing like a seasoned pro!"
    </string>
    <string name="advance4" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">

"Line three kicks it up a notch with triplets, where you'll play three notes per beat, maintaining the same picking pattern. If you're craving a speed challenge, line four is your sixteenth-note showdown, pushing your accuracy and speed to the limit. Remember, start at a slower pace, ensuring clean notes and a steady rhythm before cranking up the tempo.

Mastering the A natural minor scale on your guitar can be achieved by exploring it in
        various positions, experimenting with alternative picking patterns, and introducing a
        metronome for timing precision. This exercise unlocks a world of melodic possibilities."
  </string>
    <string name="advance4a" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        The <b>pentatonic scale</b>, a musical ladder with five distinct notes within an octave, is a simple, catchy, and omnipresent scale found in rock, blues, and folk music.
  </string>
    <string name="advance4b" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"The pentatonic scale, with its five notes, is easy to learn and universally pleasing, making it ideal for beginners or those looking to navigate the musical landscape without getting lost in a maze of notes. It allows for versatile jamming, improvising, and constructing captivating melodies, making it a musical Swiss Army Knife.

Explore the pentatonic scale's simplicity and versatility, suitable for beginners
        and experienced players, allowing the fretboard to serve as a gateway to musical exploration."
</string>
    <string name="advance5" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">

"Let's Break it Down: There are two main types of pentatonic scales:"
</string>
    <string name="advance5a" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"Choose a Starting Note: Begin by selecting any note that resonates with you. For our example, let's start with C."
</string>
    <string name="advance5b" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
Skip Up Three Notes: Progress to E, then skip over F and head to G.
</string>
    <string name="advance5c" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
Skip Another Two Notes: Bypass A and B, and land on D.
</string>
    <string name="advance5d" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"Go Down One Note: Return to C, completing the sequence. Congratulations! You've just built a C major pentatonic scale: C, D, E, G, C.
Explore the pentatonic scale on guitar or other instruments, embracing mistakes and creativity. Use the scale as a
        musical playground and enjoy exploring and experimenting."
</string>
    <string name="advance5e" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
        Pentatonic Scale Exercise Sample
    </string>
    <string name="advance5f" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
"Get ready to delve into the simplicity and versatility of the pentatonic scale. Whether you're a beginner seeking an easy entry into music or an experienced player looking to expand your sonic toolkit, the Pentatonic Playground is your gateway to musical exploration. So, dive in, let the fretboard be your playground, and enjoy the musical journey!

These five positions, showcased in the tablature, can be shifted up or down the neck to
        play the scale in different keys."
    </string>
    <string name="advance6" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">

Practice Exercise

        </string>
    <string name="advance6a" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
Slow Scale Playthrough: Begin by playing the pentatonic scale slowly in each of the five positions. Focus on precise fingering, ensuring clean notes.
</string>
    <string name="advance6b" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
Varied Order Play: Experiment with different scale positions, either ascending from the bottom to the top or descending from the top to the bottom, once comfortable with each.
</string>
    <string name="advance6c" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
Rhythmic Variations: Introduce rhythmic diversity by playing the scale in different rhythms, such as eighth notes, triplets, or sixteenth notes.
        </string>
    <string name="advance6d" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">

        Tips for Effective Practice:
The metronome is a crucial tool for improvement in the technique of playing the scale, as it helps maintain a steady tempo and enhances timing. Regular practice sessions and self-analysis can help identify areas for improvement, ensuring a smoother performance.
</string>

    <string name="advance6e" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
Remember, The pentatonic scale is a crucial element in improvisation,
        and consistent practice can enhance the skills required for solos.
</string>

    <string name="advance6f" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
<b>Blues Scale</b>
</string>

    <string name="advance7" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
The blues scale is a unique musical scale used in blues music that
        incorporates the "blue note" into a regular minor or major pentatonic scale,
        producing a distinctly bluesy sound.

While there are various blues scale variations. two of the mose prevalent are:
        </string>
    <string name="advance7a" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
The <b>minor blues scale</b>, a key element in blues music, features a flattened fifth, r
        esulting in a melancholic and expressive sound
        </string>
    <string name="advance7b" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">

        The <b>major blues scale</b> adds a flattened third to the major pentatonic scale, imparting a more
        upbeat and playful vibe often found in blues, rock, and country genres.
</string>
    <string name="advance7c" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">
Blues scales are utilized in soloing, improvisation, and melodies to provide a bluesy character and increase expressiveness through subtle bends in the "blue notes."
    </string>
    <string name="offer">Offer</string>
    <string name="user_sign_up">User Sign-up</string>
    <string name="tutor_sign_up">Tutor Sign_up</string>

</resources>